A Guide to the Manuscripts of James Branch Cabell 1921-1936
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Maunscripts of James Branch Cabell, 1921-1936
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-e
Microfilm.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on June 20, 1959 for microfilming. The originals were returned to Cornell University Library.
Scope and Content Information
In this collection of letters, James Branch Cabell discusses The American Spectator, a publication which he co-edited along with George Jean Nathan and others. Cabell gives his opinion and makes recommendations and corrections on articles to be published in the Spectator. Discussing American authors, Cabell gives his views on William Faulkner, Upton Sinclair, and Ambrose Bierce. Cabell also compliments Nathan on his Autobiography of an Attitude and mentions his own Ladies and Gentlemen.
This collection is on microfilm (M-1530), from originals in Cornell University Library.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the order in which they appear on the microfilm.
Contents List
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan October 3, 1925, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan October 23, 1926, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to ( ) Boyd and Nathan February 2, 1933, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan April 12, 1933, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan June 3, 1933, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan October 6, 1933, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to Boyd and George Jean Nathan February 10, 1934, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan October 9, 1934, TLS, 1 p.
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan April 17, 1935, TLS, 1935
- James Branch Cabell to George Jean Nathan May 5, 1935, TLS, 1 p.